A Guide to the Carl T. Herakovich Papers, 1973-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Carl T. Herakovich Papers, 1973-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1987-033
1 box; 1.0 cu. ft.
The collection includes budget and renewal reports for the Composite Materials Research and Education Program at Virginia Tech. The collection also contains similar proposals for several other similar ventures.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Carl T. Herakovich Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1987.
Biographical Information
Carl T. Herakovich was a professor in the Engineering Science and Mechanics Department at Virginia Tech from 1967-1987, and also served as the co-director of the NASA-Virginia Tech Composite Materials Research and Education Program from 1974-1984. A brief biography of his career before and after Virginia Tech is available here.
Scope and Content
The collection includes budget and renewal reports for the Composite Materials Research and Education Program at Virginia Tech. The collection also contains similar proposals for several other similar ventures.
A majority of this collection contains proposals, renewals, and reports related to the Composite Materials Research and Education program (NASA Grant NGR 47-004-129) at Virginia Tech in the 1970s and 1980s. Also included are posters and papers from speakers in conjunction with the program, personnel appointments, and some internal memos and correspondence.
Additional topic files relate to proposals on "Research in High Temperature Composite Materials for Aerospace Structures," "Acoustic Emission Investigation of Composite Reinforced Metals," "Aeronautics and Air Transportation Systems," and "Advanced Design Concepts Using Composite Materials."
Arrangement
The collection has been maintained in its original order. One additional folder (13a) has been added to hold loose items found between folders 13 and 14.
In the "Contents List" below, additional information regarding folder contents has been added in brackets. Composite Materials Research and Education folders are listed, followed by other specific NASA proposals and projects, then general NASA and VPI files.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography of Publications in Special Collections
Avery, William B., and Carl T. Herakovich. A Study of the Mechanical Behavior of a 2-D Carbon-Carbon Composite. Blacksburg, Va: Center for Composite Materials and Structures, College of Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1987. Rare Book Collection: Spec VT General LD5655.A652 C4 1987a
Barbe, Andre, and Carl T. Herakovich. A Critical Assessment of Crack Growth Criteria in Unidirectional Composites. Blacksburg, Va: Center for Composite Materials and Structures, College of Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University, 1985. LD5655.A652 C4 1985b
Fox, Derek J., George F. Sykes, and Carl T. Herakovich. Space Environmental Effects on Graphite-Epoxy Compressive Properties and Epoxy Tensile Properties. Blacksburg, Va: Center for Composite Materials and Structures, College of Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1987. Rare Book Collection: Spec VT General LD5655.A652 C4 1987b
Kadiyala, Srinivas Prasad, Zafer Gürdal, and Carl T. Herakovich. An Experimental and Numerical Study of Notch Sensitivity of ARALL Laminates. Blacksburg, Va: College of Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1988. Rare Book Collection: Spec VT General LD5655.A652 C4 1988
Norwood, Donald Scott, Mark J. Shuart, and Carl T. Herakovich. An Analysis of Interlaminar Stresses in Unsymmetrically Laminated Plates. Blacksburg, Va: College of Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1990. Rare Book Collection: Spec VT General LD5655.A651 A912 no.90-18
Strauss, Elizabeth Ann, and Carl T. Herakovich. Finite Element Analysis of Damaged Cross-Ply Composite Laminates. Blacksburg, Va: Center for Composite Materials and Structures, College of Engineering, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1987. Rare Book Collection: Spec VT General LD5655.A652 C4 1987c
Contents List
- Proposal - Composite Materials Research and Education, 1973-1974. (Box-folder 1:4)
- 1st Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1974-1975.
- 2nd Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1975-1976. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1976-1977. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1977-1978. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1978-1979. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1979-1980. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1980-1981. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Renewal Proposal [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1981-1982. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Reports [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1974-1980. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Budget Approvals [Composite Materials Research and Education], 1977-1985. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Distinguished Lecturers, 1977-1986. (Box-folder 1:14)
- [Composite Materials Research and Education Information Posters], n.d. (Box-folder 1:13a)
- NVTCP [NASA Virginia Tech Composites Program] - June-December, 1986. (Box-folder 1:22)
- NVTCP, 1987. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Proposal: Acoustic Emission Investigation of Composite Reinforced Metals, 1973. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Final Report NAS1-1-646-17 Acoustic Emission Investigation of Composite Reinforced Metals, 1973. (Box-folder 1:16)
- Reports [NASA Grant NGR-47-004-090 Aeronautics and Air Transportation Systems and NASA Grant NGR-47-004-090-118 Viscoelastic-Plastic Behavior of Adhesives for Composite Bonding], 1974-1977. (Box-folder 1:17)
- NSG 1250 - Research in High Temperature Composite Materials for Aerospace Structures, 1975-1976. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Reports - NASA NCC1-15, 1982-1985. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Young - Advanced Design Concepts Using Composite Materials/NASA - VPI-11-110F-105-313155-1, 1987. (Box-folder 1:25)
- Appointments [Personnel], 1975-1986. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Loos, Herakovich, Hyers [Correspondence and proposals], 1983-1984. (Box-folder 1:19)
- NASA Materials - Annual Reports, 1982-1987. (Box-folder 1:21)
- NASA Materials [Internal VPI memos and proposals], 1984-1986. (Box-folder 1:18)
- NASA Materials [Proposals], 1986. (Box-folder 1:20)